<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Attributio | Business Intelligence &amp; Analytics Experts</title>
    <link>https://attribut.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Attributio | Business Intelligence &amp; Analytics Experts</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://attribut.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Acheive Multi-Touch Attribution For Your Company</title>
      <link>https://attribut.io/multi-touch-attribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://attribut.io/multi-touch-attribution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-marketing-attribution&#34;&gt;What is marketing attribution?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, marketing attribution is giving credit to the source that leads to a sale.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The source can consist of ads, referrals, campaigns, or even salesmen. And the sale can be anything from an action on your website to a conversion that generates leads to an actual purchase.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-attribution-mean-in-marketing&#34;&gt;What does attribution mean in marketing?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Marketing is more art than science. However, with proper attribution, professional marketers can come closer to making marketing more scientific by collecting and measuring where their sales and conversions are coming from.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Paid Ads Really Work?</title>
      <link>https://attribut.io/do-paid-ads-really-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://attribut.io/do-paid-ads-really-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-channels-convert&#34;&gt;What Channels Convert?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled in digital advertising and content marketing, you might find that your advertisers&amp;rsquo; attribution reports don&amp;rsquo;t line up. That&amp;rsquo;s because they want credit for your conversions so you&amp;rsquo;ll spend more on their platforms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever looked at a Google Analytics report, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that either you have a lot of Direct traffic or if you have some content, you get a lot of conversions through Organic traffic. The problem with these reports is that attribution is often defined within a 30 day window and attribution is based on a last-click model so you&amp;rsquo;ll never really know where your visitors originated from.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Measure ROI with Salesforce &amp; Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://attribut.io/the-ultimate-guide-to-measure-roi-with-salesforce-and-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://attribut.io/the-ultimate-guide-to-measure-roi-with-salesforce-and-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;brand-marketing-vs-direct-marketing&#34;&gt;Brand Marketing VS Direct Marketing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t manage what you can&amp;rsquo;t measure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- Peter Drucker&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We live in an age when we can measure just about everything. The fact that many of us aren&amp;rsquo;t measuring our direct marketing efforts is detrimental to our businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brand marketing continues to be difficult to measure since brand marketing is more about communicating values to an audience. The ROI on that kind of advertising is measured far down the line whereas direct marketing is about getting conversions and selling right off the bat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Offline Sales in Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://attribut.io/tracking-offline-sales-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://attribut.io/tracking-offline-sales-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;configure-your-lead-generation-forms-to-store-googles-cookies&#34;&gt;Configure your lead generation forms to store Google&amp;rsquo;s cookies&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re collecting leads online and converting them over the phone through your CRM, you need to collect a cookie that Google Analytics sets on your website to identify that user. Once you store that unique id in your CRM, you can send a webhook to Google Analytics with that id via their &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Measurement Protocol&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; whenever a deal has been completed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Unblock Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://attribut.io/unblock-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://attribut.io/unblock-google/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;adblockers&#34;&gt;Adblockers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adblocking is on the rise. And with it comes not only the removal of ads but the blocking of popular web traffic tracking tools like Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some reports suggest that more than 10% of all web traffic is now being blocked from services like Google Analytics and this can be a major issue for businesses that rely on accurate data to make good business decisions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;specific-problems&#34;&gt;Specific Problems&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You might find that the conversions being reported in Google Analytics don&amp;rsquo;t actually reflect the conversions that you are seeing in the backend of your website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Goals with Subdomains in Google Analytics</title>
      <link>https://attribut.io/tracking-goals-with-subdomains-in-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://attribut.io/tracking-goals-with-subdomains-in-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes your conversion funnel spans multiple domains or subdomains. If you need to track destination url goals on a subdomain for an existing universal analytics property, you can follow the steps below to distinguish between root domain visitors and subdomain visitors along with goals that might have the same url path. This is not to be confused with cross-domain tracking which requires different configuration settings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1---set-cookie-domain-to-auto&#34;&gt;Step 1 - Set cookie domain to auto&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add the universal analytics tracking code from your root domain to your subdomain and ensure that the cookie domain is set to auto (by default it is set in universal analytics unless you are using GTM).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Track Conversions With Google Analytics&#39; Client ID &amp; User ID</title>
      <link>https://attribut.io/track-conversions-with-google-analytics-client-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://attribut.io/track-conversions-with-google-analytics-client-id/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics is an underutilized tool and there are a few basic things you can do to gain more insight into your conversions. Last year in March of 2016 Google made their new &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;User Explorer&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; available to the public. It&amp;rsquo;s a great tool but unfortunately, you can&amp;rsquo;t drill down into other dimensions with this tool yet. Also, you can&amp;rsquo;t combine this information with other dimensions or metrics like where the user came from.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
